Let's make some cool furniture 与 simulations.
So I'm going to 开始 by making a 平面 so we can have a 碰撞体 there.
I'm going to 隐藏 the 摄像机 because I don't want that to bother me 右 now.
右 now what I'm going to do is I'm just going to 创建 something that feels organic and abstract.
Imagine that you 回车键 a museum and you see a big sofa that's in the 进入 hall.
So that's what we're going to do.
And then 之后 that maybe we can 目标点 doing something that feels a little more grounded in reality in a way.
Something like an armchair for example.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to grab a 样条.
Let's go to 顶视图.
By the way, I still miss the icons for that stuff.
Let's make a 快速 样条.
I'm not going to get too much into 细节 because we'll probably refine it anyway.
Let's 后退 to 透视.
I don't want to see 灯光, I don't want to see anything.
Let's 移动 it a little bit 朝向 the middle.
Yeah, it's not looking that bad.
Nothing to worry 关于 at this moment.
So let's 翻转 this bad boy.
Let's 添加 a 圆形.
And well, we have this.
And you'll think this is useless.
Well, it is now.
Let's try to 添加 some cups.
Sorry, the dog is barking in the 背景.
So everything is more rounded.
Honestly, I'm not too worried 关于 intersections here because I would probably put this into a borderline 破碎/分裂 anyway.
But I'm worried 关于 this part here.
Let's make it a 柔和 插值.
Honestly, I'm just going to tweak it a little bit because...
I don't know. I kind of like it when it collides because once you drop it into the 体积网格, it looks like it has some kind of wrinkles in a way.
Yeah, we don't have to worry 关于 it being too 关闭 because 与 the 模拟, it's eventually going to 扩大.
So let's drop this into a borderline 破碎/分裂.
And yeah, we have this kind of 模式, which is not exactly what we are looking for.
右 now, I'm going to try and 使用 it 与 this 点 生成器 分配.
I don't want to have a lot of cuts because the more we have, the less realistic it's going to look.
So let's go for three.
And let's 偏移 the fragments a little bit so we have some spacing in between them.
So, okay, I think this can work.
Let's just keep moving forward.
Let's remerge that.
So we are starting to have more quad 几何.
Even though it's not perfect, it will probably work for our purposes.
We could either 细分 it here a bit more.
I think I'm going to actually do 两者.
And then maybe we need to actually 细分 it here too.
But maybe not as much.
Let's give it a go 与 this and see how it looks.
So we are going to go and simulate this.
Let's put a cloth of somebody.
Let's try 与 the cloth.
Because we actually need it to be a balloon.
And we need to 添加 some overpressure so it grows.
Go 到帧 zero.
I think it works.
This is actually a little bit of a bummer.
If you have this 禁用, it won't work.
Okay, looks like shit.
Let's 添加 a 碰撞体 to the 地面.
It's not looking as bad.
Trust me, it could be worse.
I think that maybe we have a lot of overpressure and it's happening too 快速 maybe.
So maybe we are going to need 75 帧.
Let's try 与 something that feels subtler for now.
Okay.
Yeah, that's a little bit better.
Actually, you know what?
Maybe it will be worth...
What's going on here?
Okay, this is 从不 going to work.
Well, we have this done.
We'll 适合 it in a 秒.
But what I'm going to do is I'm going to 移除 the 重力.
And we need to check this motherfucker.
So remember everything that I said 关于 that corner looking great and blah blah?
Well, we actually need to 适合 it.
Okay, let's try again.
Okay, this is better.
Without any 重力, it's going to be just better to simulate it.
But as you can see, things are going away.
It's a fun 模拟, but absolutely worthless as it is 右 now.
So what we need to do is that we need to 添加 some mixed 动画.
And what I like to do is I put it by 强度.
And if you 选集 it to just one, it will try to keep its 放置.
So as you can see now, everything stays in the same 放置, which is really cool.
And maybe we can 开始 experimenting 与 this if we want to get some wrinkles and stuff like that.
Well, we are getting this abstract 形状.
Honestly, not a fan of it 右 now, but one thing that we can and we should do...
第一 of all, let's put the 目标 长度 a little bit higher so we get more wrinkles too.
I think this is going to do too much, but we have to try.
Well, yeah, but we 开始 to get some more wrinkles here and there.
It's true that maybe we need some more 几何.
So let's try to actually get rid of the 细分曲面.
We will probably need it later, but once we have simulated.
Of course, more 多边形 means it's going to be slower, but the 分辨率 of the 模拟 is going to be more realistic.
Yeah, 第一 帧 are looking worse, but we are getting much more 细节 everywhere.
And this is starting to look much, much cooler.
One thing that we can do actually, it's in 次序 to simulate where people will actually sit.
I like to put a 碰撞体 on top, which is going to be 不可见, but it's going to be useful to 创建 more of a sitting 区域 on 上.
And let's say we like it there.
As you can see, this way we are starting to get something that can be actually used as an abstract sofa or something like that.
Probably we have to 添加 an 边 here.
That's why it's causing that.
So maybe we can try and 添加 a little bit more 圆角 just so things are a little bit smoother everywhere.
Let's 隐藏 this marker.
Yeah, you can see th@Part is much better now.
And this stuff can be actually 细分 now.
And we have this kind of organic.
Probably the 下 of it is also looking really cool.
We have these really, really cool 形状 with a lot of 细节.
And these are looking amazing.
And this can actually be applied to any kind of 形状.
I'm just doing it in this abstract way because I found that the results are a little bit cooler.
But yeah, it's a really abstract and cool looking sofa.
I have to say I love it. I really love it.
So the cool thing 关于 this is that it's quite 程序.
So I'm going to duplicate this and make sure that I 禁用 the simulations.
And the cool thing is that we can make whatever we want 与 it.
So if we want to 开始 moving things around, it's going to crash because it's C4d.
It's on me, actually. I have a lot of stuff.
So we have the boron refractory, which we can still 编辑.
And we can try as many different 形状 as we want.
Well, this part here is looking really lovely.
Mostly this part here goes back that, but well, probably because of this reason.
So what we can do is actually put this inside a 体积...
What am I doing?
体积生成器 and a volume measure.
Let's give it more... not space, but 分辨率.
And we can try and see this, how it looks.
We have more triangles 右 now, so the 模拟 is way, way more organic.
But it kind of mimics a 生长 模拟, which is also really fucking sick.
It's a little bit disgusting, too.
Wow, so sick.
I'm going to grab a still of this.
Lovely. Disgusting, but lovely.
And if we 细分 it, it's going to be a little bit tighter, but let's see.
Yeah, it's a little bit unbearable to work 与.
But it creates a really, really organic 形状.
And 目标点 this 下 part is looking so sick.
I think it has actually skipped...
Yeah, it has skipped the 地面 because I forgot to put the 碰撞体 there.
But it's also cool what it's creating there.
To be fair, it's quite... I have to 停止 looking at it.
It looks disgusting.
Yeah, too much 几何, but it's all 右.
It's all 右.
And the cool thing 关于 this technique is that you can apply it to this 样条.
You can apply it to some cubes.
But let's see it in a 秒.
What I'm going to do now is I'm going to try and 使用 this...
Let me see.
I want to make this our 碰撞体, too.
So maybe... let's see. Let's see how it works.
Well, they disappear.
Probably once we've added this...
I'm going to put back ours.
The 体积网格 maybe we need to tweak a little bit.
Especially this one because that's the one that's creating all the wrinkles.
Which again, they are looking good, but probably not what we're looking for at the moment.
They get a little bit lost too 快速.
What I'm going to try and do is I'm going to 使用 this 圆形.
Oh, shit.
It changes.
We can 添加 a 平面 to make them a little bit bigger.
This is just for testing purposes.
But let's see how it looks.
Again, we have a lot of issues here.
These 其他 parts are looking great because we have these kind of chains that are keeping the 形状 together.
But let's try, maybe we need to...
Actually, also, let's do one thing.
I'm going to 创建 an 实例 of this main 样条.
And I'm going to 替换 it with the 秒 one that's creating this.
So that way, if we 修改 one 样条, we just need to do it once.
Let's try and make a more 法线 looking...
Whatever this is.
Let's 禁用 this too.
And also the 网格重构, please.
I'm thinking th@Probably we don't need the 网格重构 here.
Because we are actually putting things inside the...
The whole 图像, anyway.
You see, it's respecting that 形状 a little bit.
It's getting fucked 上 there.
But honestly, I think that's like limitations from C4d.
It's true that also these guys here don't have a lot of 分辨率 at all.
Maybe they have a little bit more 几何.
It won't be as bad.
But well, to begin 与, they are even already colliding.
禁用 poise, that's it.
I don't know, I think it's looking really cool.
I love it.
Let's try some 其他 weird stuff.
Let's 开始 to organize things a little bit.
This is going to be B2.
This is B1.
总是 remember to 禁用 all your 动态 tags.
Otherwise, everything is going to be simulated.
For example, this stuff.
Can't it be 禁用?
That fucking sucks.
Fucking sucks.
Well, I'm going to just 移除 myself.
And actually, if you 移除 the 体积 cursor, that's going to be better.
Otherwise, it's going to 计算 it.
And this is the 碰撞体 that we are using.
This can be 全局, but I'm going to duplicate it 两者 times for this and this.
Just so I can keep track exactly of everything that's going on.
B1.
Sadly, I need to 移除 the 碰撞体 tag.
Let's try to do something that feels a little bit more 法线 in a way.
Let me reuse this.
The 第一 tag that we were using, I'm going to 启用 it.
I'm just going to press hit to see how it is.
Your 平均 looking cushion.
Let's put it in a 体积 cursor.
I'm going to try different 形状.
Let's put this in a 对称 maybe, so we are saving some 时间.
This looks like shit because it's too 低多边形.
Actually, 右 now we are creating a 生长 效果 because we are 模拟 inside the volume cursor.
This is actually also something cool to check.
You are actually creating a 生长 效果 because we are 模拟 and then we are applying the 体积网格.
It's cool, but I don't think C4d is there to be able to pull 上 these simulations.
It's actually quite cool. It can look like a foam 模拟.
At this moment it's also colliding 与 each 其他 because it's actually three different 形状.
The 结果 is actually quite cool, but it's not what I was looking for.
I was looking to 修改 this as a whole.
The 平面 right now is not working well for that reason because we have some stuff outside.
Let's try another 立方体 that we are going to put inside a folder.
I'm putting this inside a folder because I like to keep things tidy.
So every 时间 that I put something that I want to 减去, I can just put it inside of the folder and that's going to be much easier to work 与.
Cool stuff. That's really cool.
Let's keep adding 形状 to our weird looking sofa.
As you can see 右 now for this process I'm not taking into consideration anything 关于 形状.
I'm just keeping in mind proportions so I know that this could later on be applied to something real if needed.
There you go. A nice inflated sofa.
Probably we have too much of this audio. Sorry 关于 that.
If you want things to look cleaner you can have these kind of 形状 that are looking super fun too.
Otherwise these kind of 形状 are really 尖锐 to pull 上.
I think 右 now this is not so beautiful but you can tweak things just to make it look a little bit more refined I guess.
Now to be fair, I won't blame anyone but myself because the 形状 that I'm using is super ugly.
It makes no sense at all.
The proportions are all... well that's why I'm going to tweak it a little bit so we got something that looks a little bit more refined.
Let's try something like this.
I mean this is looking cooler.
Let's 添加 a little bit more 压力.
A little bit of this, a little bit of that.
Love it. This is looking much better.
And now what I'm going to do is I'm going to 使用 these 形状 that we have here and I'm going to 创建 some colliders to act like the 基础 of our chair.
So for example if we duplicate these two...
I mean this is going to be 尖锐 to give a little context like in real 生命.
But we can definitely try to make it feel a little bit more grounded in reality.
So yeah, let's do this for now.
Maybe then we can 连接 things if we need.
Let's see if it doesn't break.
Okay, it broke.
I think it worked at the beginning.
Yeah, but then it totally ignored our...
We have too much 压力 going on so let's try 与 three.
It got absolutely ignored.
Let me try to quickly...
Actually, let me try.
Yeah, I think it wasn't just working at all.
We need to attack for each of them.
Actually this one, I'm going to make it...
And you can see you have this 形状 inside of this 其他 shape.
It's just looking really cool.
Well, I'm not a super fan of this 形状 because it looks a little bit stupid to be fair.
But you can go ahead and also...
I think I broke it.
Yeah, I broke it.
I broke it because now this is our initial 几何, but well, it doesn't really matter.
So, for example, maybe what we can do 右 now, let's say this is our 形状.
We can either put it like this or it's going to collide if it goes farther.
But things are going crazy 右 now.
And we need some more colliders there, that's for sure.
So let's try to bring back the 碰撞体.
And I want to 烘焙 a 形状 out of this one.
And I'm going to...
Oops, what's happening here?
Probably we have more colliders everywhere.
Yeah, that sucks.
Yeah, I think that works better.
So maybe we don't want this huge 碰撞体.
Let's try and put this in a way so we can 创建...
Imagine this is a bench.
And I want th@Part there to be this part here and this part here.
So I can 创建 a sitting 区域 in 两者 places.
Yeah, that's looking good.
And let me get a still of this 形状.
Maple and...
Okay, so we have this as our 主要 starting 基础.
Let's try to 适合 the 几何 a little bit.
Maybe we can put a 平滑 on it.
And have a little bit more 控制 on those wrinkles.
You can see it was like this.
Maybe the font 标签 itself could work anyway.
But I think it can be used also.
There's a 平滑 deformer.
We have this weird sitting 区域.
It's looking great.
This 下 part is looking even cooler.
And actually, I just had an idea.
This can actually also be used for 3D printing as the kind of 形状 that it's creating.
This can be used, for example, as a keyholder.
Okay, I know that I'm not working in 缩放.
But you can actually...
This is your real-生命 size 关键帧.
You can actually print this motherfucker and you have a full keyholder for your plot.
As I'm going to put the models there, feel 可用 to do 与 them whatever you want.
That's what I like 关于 this kind of way of designing things.
I actually don't need to think much.
I'm just experimenting 与 it.
And whatever that comes out works for me.
If I'm making a sofa, let's say...
I'm 总是 making a sofa just to 显示 the technique.
But if I'm making a sofa and then I come 上 与 this idea...
This is actually a fucking win because it's actually even a cooler idea than the previous one, you know?
Well, yeah.
It's enough for the struggles a little bit.
It's very useful to 放置 things correctly.
But you can see it can be quite a nice thing to have laying around in your flat.
I love it.
But that wasn't what I was planning to 显示.
I was planning to 显示 how we can actually make this look more comfy.
So, let's make another 立方体.
And let's make a pillow out of this one.
Let's 开始 with a 规律 sized one.
I want to 使用 these guys as a 碰撞体.
And...
We need more 几何 here.
If you 选择 both press ctrl and 牵引场, you will 添加 more 部分 to each side.
Let's put this as a 云.
And...
Oops.
Sorry, there's already way too many.
And you 创建 a fillet and then you give this some inflation.
It will struggle because it's too 细薄.
You give it a little more air.
It still struggles because it's so 细薄 that you need to give it a little bit less 厚度.
Let's try 与 5.
Okay, yeah.
It's breaking.
Not sure why, but let's 查找 out.
Probably let's try without 圆角.
So, let's give it a little bit more 部分 here.
And we need way more inflation.
Cool.
We have something that starts to look like a cushion.
I want it to be a bit thinner though.
Let me see if I can actually get it to work 与 圆角.
Because I know that 圆角 helps...
Well, fuck it.
Well, more 几何 means that we need a little bit more inflation too.
I don't know why it's doing that kind of motion.
Maybe this 时间 we need some more 其他 通道.
Let's put the 减震 a little bit higher.
Yeah, that works better.
So, what I'm going to do is I'm going to actually...
第一 of all, I'm going to duplicate this motherfucker.
I'm going to put it here.
I'm going to 旋转 it a little bit to 创建 some more copies.
Let's do something 与 it.
Well, that one that I scaled 下, I'm not sure if I'm going to need to 更新 it.
But let's go to the 模拟 settings and let's go to, for example, 边框 60.
And here we are going to put the 重力 to be on.
Two 帧 之前, it's going to be 关闭.
This way we're going to get an inflation 动画 and then the cushions are going to go 下.
So they become cushions then go 下.
And this way you can actually, well, I think...
It's not working because we have a 碰撞体 here.
But I think it's super easy to solidly 生成 a lot of cushions.
It's not working still because there's probably some 其他 hidden 碰撞体 over there.
Colliding...
These are not it.
This one.
Okay, now it finally works.
But this is cool because you can actually 创建 a lot of them.
I'm surprised by how well C4d handles this.
Honestly, I would have 从不 expected it to work that well.
I have a lot of them 右 now.
It's going to break for a little bit, but as you can see, it's still working quite, quite well.
So now they are inflated and they go 下.
You can 创建 like a pillow party.
So 与 this technique, I created this chair, for example, that you're seeing here on the 右.
I just tried to resume it because this is how it was looking.
And I think there's something wrong because this is my 基础 形状.
These are my colliders, which are just basically like a 盒子 and a 盒子 inside a 立方体.
I think it's currently not looking exactly the same.
Ah, yeah, maybe it doesn't. Let's give it a go.
So I did the same technique. I basically created a 基础 形状, which I was then inflating, and then it's colliding.
But yeah, you know, C4d has this tendency of tweaking things.
And suddenly when you open a file that you were working on from six months ago, suddenly it's not working.
Yeah, this looks like shit. I'm not sure if the remix is going to get 固定.
It's not. You see? It's like, well, you got a home and want to 次序 online.
But yeah, this kind of 形状 and organicness looks really cool to me. I honestly quite love it.
Being able to 创建 these abstract-looking, more organic 形状.